HUGO ARRIOJAS

Front-End Web Developer

(647)-339-3480 hugo.arriojas@hotmail.com Ottawa, ON HugoA.dev Github.com/HugoArriojas Linkedin.com/in/HugoArriojas

PROFILE

I am a front-end web developer and marine biologist with experience in data analytics, accounting, and customer service roles.

I enjoy applying my skills in order to create responsive and user-friendly apps in React and Javascript.

With my experience in project management and strong presentation skills, I aim to bring our design to life while still maintaining a focus on accessibility.

SKILLS

Web Development

- HTML
- RESTful APIs
- CSS
- Firebase
- SCSS

- · Git collaboration
- React
- Version Control
- Figma
- Project Scope Management

Data Analytics

- R / RStudio
- MATLAB
- ANVIO

Design

- Photoshop
- Lightroom
- Premiere Pro

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent Spanish - Fluent

French - Basic

EDUCATION

Juno College of Technology September 2021 to December 2021 Web Development Immersive Bootcamp & Javascript Course

Dalhousie University

September 2013 to April 2017

Honours Bachelor of Science in Marine Biology & Statistics

PROJECTS

Reactive Retail

Git, React, SASS, HTML, CSS, Figma

Reactive Retail is a mock retail site built entirely in React using the FakeStore API. In the app, users are able to filter through a variety of products via category and then convert product prices to different currencies.

Live Link: bit.ly/ReactiveRetail Git Repo: bit.ly/ReactiveRetailGit

The Not So Social Planner Git branching, React, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Figma

This React group project works as a social planner wherein users are able to submit recurring weekly events into a calendar. Should the user choose to not go through with their social commitments, they are able to check out what shows are streaming at the time. This project simulates an agency-style environment, the project scope being outlined in a client brief

Live Link: bit.ly/NotSocialPlanner Git Repo: bit.ly/NotSocialPlannerGit

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Accounting Administrator

March 2018 to July 2021

Carson Auto Group, Victoria Ford Alliance

- Reviewed and reconciled banking, warranty, and inventory accounts using CDK software, taking care of hundreds of clients spanning 5 large car dealerships.
- Worked with a team to maintain a large database of records using a variety of accounting software in order to track deals, payments, and inventory.
- Spearheaded several projects to increase efficiency in the workplace and aimed to create a standardized method for future workers that may hold the role.

At-Sea Fisheries Observer

January 2018 to November 2018

Archipelago Marine Research

- Gathered, verified, audited, and reported biological and commercial catch data for the Department of Fisheries and Oceans while working in extreme
- Produced detailed & adaptive cruise reports and program summaries while living onboard foreign vessels for extended periods of time.